今晚的课真是太完美了
Oh, I had the most exquisite class this evening.
我的学生们在排练
My students are rehearsing
《灵欲春宵》里拳击的那场戏
the boxing scene from "Who's afraid of Virginia Woolf?"
我只庆幸他们用的是你的工作室
I'm just glad they were using your studio
而不是我的卧室
and not my living room.
你在给我做你拿手的烤意面配干酪土司
Oh, you're making me your fabulous pasta carbonara.
你不用这么费心的
Ohh. You shouldn't have.
不是给你的
I didn't.
实际上是给阿丽克西斯的
Actually, it's for Alexis.
她最近太忙了
She's just been, you know, so busy lately.
我想借机联络感情
I thought we'd, uh, reconnect.
所以做了她最爱吃的
Mm. So her favorite dish,
然后再一起看《电锯惊魂4》的导演剪辑版
and then a screening of "Saw iv," the director's cut.
我真不忍心告诉你  亲爱的  她不会回来了
Uh, I hate to tell you this, darling, but she won't be here.
什么意思  她还能去哪里
What do you mean? Where else would she be?
她又开始新的实习工作了
She's starting a new internship.
又换了个
Another one?
她确实说过她想试些新鲜事物来找到她的激情
She did say she wanted to try a few things to find her passion.
现在是九点
It's 9:00 o'clock.
她这个时候能找到什么样的激情
What kind of passion is she finding at this time of night?
你的另一半来电了
Aha. There. Your better half.
别转移话题
Don't change the subject.
她到底在实习什么
What is this internship exactly?
理查德  阿丽克西斯让我发誓保密的
Richard, Alexis swore me to secrecy.
是  可身为她的父亲
Yes, but as her father--
我的嘴可闭得死死的
Ah, ah, ah, ah. My lips are sealed.
那你就吃不了我的烤意面配干酪吐司了
Then you won't be using them to eat my... pasta carbonara.
好吧  我这么说吧
All right. Well, let me say this.
她这份实习是经过我亲自批准的
This internship has my personal seal of approval.
这并没能让我舒坦点
That doesn't make me feel any better.
其实  问题不在于她去实习
The truth is, the internship isn't the problem.
而是她已经找了三份实习工作了
It's the fact, she now has three of them.
说不准呢  卡塞尔
Yeah, well, you never know, Castle.
这一份可能会以某种方式
This might be the one that brings the two of you
拉近你们俩的关系
closer together somehow.
可能不大  我只期望
I doubt it. The best I could hope for now is,
她能学会屈居他人之下
she learns to become more of an underachiever.
对  你肯定能给她点建议
Yeah. Well, I'm sure you'll be able to give her some tips.
情况是...
So...
邻居们听到激烈的打斗声
neighbors heard a hellacious fight,
然后死者
and then our victim here
从那扇四层的窗户掉下来
sailed out of that fourth-floor window.
那是他的公寓吗
Was that his apartment?
我们在查  可看上去不像
We're checking, but it doesn't look like it.
住户们不认识他  他也没有任何证件
Tenants don't recognize him and he doesn't have any I.D.
没证件  可死因有很多
No I.D., but lots of causes of death.
你是说除了坠楼
You mean other than gravity?
对
Oh, yeah.
看到那处枪伤吗
See that bullet wound?
那他在坠楼前遭枪击
So he was shot before he fell?
还挨刀子了
And stabbed.
又遭枪击又挨刀
Shot and stabbed?
还有勒伤
And choked,
脖子一边还插了支铅笔
and has a pencil jammed in the side of his neck.
给"过度杀戮"冠以了的新的定义
Ah. Gives new meaning to the term "overkill."
有人看到攻击他的人吗
Did anyone see his attacker?
我们在询问目击者
Uh, we're checking with witnesses,
但我想凶手应该是趁乱
but I figure that our perp slipped out of the building
溜出楼的
during all the confusion.
好  我们去看看他们的进展
All right. Let's go see what they got.
晚上好  阿丽克西斯
Hey, Alexis.
阿丽克西斯
Alexis?
老爸
Hey, dad.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
这...
Is...
这就是你新找的实习
is this your new internship?
帕里什医生同意让我跟着她
Dr. Parish agreed to let me shadow her.
我想  如果我要去医学院
I thought, if I go to med school,
这能让我对法医病理学有更清楚的了解
this will give me a better grasp of forensic pathology.
这两天我就学到了很多
I've learned so much in just two days.
亲爱的
Sweetie...
你为什么不告诉我
Why wouldn't you tell me?
我想我是怕你不同意
I guess I was afraid you'd veto it,
或许你会觉得我来这里
like maybe you'd think me being here
是在侵犯你的地盘  或者...
was invading your territory or--
什么
What?
太扯了  我怎么可能那么想
That's crazy. I wouldn't... think that.
真是...
That's...
这真是太好了
This is great.
-是啊  -我只是不知
- Yeah. - It's--I just--I don't know
让你目睹犯罪现场和死尸会不会不合适
if you should be exposed to crime scenes and dead bodies.
我已经习惯了
Oh, I'm already used to it.
虽恶心但也很酷
It's equal parts gross and cool.
我听到了  我完全赞同你的看法
I heard that and I couldn't agree with you more.
我终于知道你为什么那么喜欢这个了  老爸
I finally get why you're into this, dad.
现在我也喜欢了
Now I'm into it, too.
太好了
That's great.
很好
Great.
我生活的分区相撞了
My worlds are colliding.
你是指阿丽克西斯
You mean Alexis?
你知道这事
You knew about this?
得了吧  卡塞尔  是你自己说
Come on, Castle. You're the one who said you wanted
想找办法和她多待会儿的
to find a way of spending more time with her.
不是这种方式
Not like this.
这是我的地盘
This is my thing.
我们的地盘
This is our thing.
这是对宗教和国家的侵犯
It's a violation of church and state.
这就好像我去她学校教书
This would be like me just showing up at her school and teaching.
我真的认为你反应有点大
I really think that you're overreacting.
如果没有呢
But what if I'm not?
如果这影响了我们微妙的合作关系呢
What if this upsets the delicate synergy of our partnership?
如果破坏了我们的团队凝聚力呢
What if it undermines our unit cohesion?
是吧  是个大问题呢
See? Major problem.
-没说那个  是这个  -地上好多血
- Not that. This. - That's a lot of blood.
有个目击证人看到一个男人离开大楼
One of our witnesses saw a man leaving the building.
他一瘸一拐的
He was limping.
嫌犯受伤了
Our suspect was injured.
一路走向那边
And the trail goes that way.
一个残忍的杀手却被自己身体的脆弱出卖了
A brutal killer betrayed by the frailty of his own flesh.
原始血迹泄露了他的行踪
His path revealed by that most primal stain.
但是行迹到此为止
Except the path ends here.
这么多血只滴在一个地方
Multiple drops in one spot?
他一定在这里停留过
He must have stood here for a minute.
他上了车
He got into a car.
如果他上了车  或许会被录下来
Well, if he did, maybe he got caught on tape.
第一通报警电话是8点42分打进来的
The first 9-1-1 call came at 8:42,
就在死者坠楼之后
just after our victim crash landed.
所以凶手可能就在一两分钟后走到了街角
So our guy probably made it to the corner a minute or two later.
阿丽克西斯来实习挺不错啊
Hey. Pretty cool about Alexis' internship.
或许不太好
Or not.
看  那个肯定就是他
There. That's gotta be him.
他受伤了  警察都在追捕他
He's wounded, the cops are after him,
他在找地方藏身
and he's looking for a place to go.
他劫了个人质
He has a hostage.
追踪出租车牌号  查明去向
Track the taxi off the medallion number, find out where it went.
纽约警察  把手举起来
NYPD! Let me see your hands!
-纽约警察  把手举起来  -起来
- NYPD! Hands in the air. - Get up.
把手举起来
Show us your hands.
起来  把手举起来
Get up. Hands in the air.
起来  起来
Get up. Get up.
双手抱头
Put your hands on your head.
立即双手抱头
Hands on your head now.
跪下
Drop to your knees.
托马斯·盖奇
Thomas Gage.
以备查证  我宣读过你的权利吗
For the record, have I advised you of your rights?
读了
Yes.
包括你请律师的权利
Including your right to an attorney?
我不需要
I won't need one.
你认识这个人吗
Do you recognize this man?
看来他摔得很惨
Looks like he took a nasty fall.
是有人推了他一把
Well, he had a little help.
指纹能证明他是被人扔出窗外
Fingerprint evidence will show that he was thrown out a window
被你扔出窗外
by you.
事后
After which,
监控摄像头将你绑架蒂娜·马赛的过程尽收眼底
you kidnapped Tina Massey in full view of a security camera.
杀人  外加绑架
Murder, plus kidnapping,
你得死在大牢里了
that equals more years in prison than you have left.
除非你肯合作
Unless you cooperate.
你们掌握的有关我的证据
Everything that you have on me...
或是你们以为有的证据
Or you think you have...
都会消失无踪
It's all going away.
我说完了
And we're done here.
这家伙应该吓得汗如雨下
This guy should be sweating bullets.
感觉很不对
This doesn't feel right.
就好像他知道我们不知道的事
It's like he knows something we don't.
尽力去查出托马斯·盖奇的所有资料
I want you to pull everything you can on Thomas Gage.
问题是  这不是他的真名
The problem is, that's not his real name.
他的驾照是伪造的
His driver's license is bogus,
系统里也没他的指纹
and his prints aren't in the system.
总之  我们对此人一无所知
Bottom line is, we have no idea who this man is.
整个过程中他一直非常冷静
The guy was super calm the whole time.
话也不多
Not big on chitchat either.
他的开场白是
His opening line was,
"滚进出租车  不然就毙了你"
"Get your ass in the cab, or I'll kill you."
那你们回到你的公寓之后呢
And what about when you went back to your apartment,
他说什么了
what did he talk about?
他保证会留我一命之后
After he promised not to murder me,
就让我包扎他的腿
he asked me to patch up his leg.
他腿上有条很深的伤口
He had a real gash.
你能看出来他是怎么伤的吗
Could you tell how he got the injury?
他说他在行凶杀人时
He said he got slashed with a knife
被对方用刀砍伤
while he was killing a guy.
他就这么供认不讳
And he admitted that to you?
更像是陈述事实
More like just made the statement.
他有没有说那人是谁
And did he say who this guy was
或者他为什么杀他
or why he killed him?
他就只跟我说  这个人不存在
All he told me was that the man doesn't exist.
这个人不存在
The man doesn't exist
至少我查不到
as far as I can tell.
那你还没查到他的身份
So you haven't I.D.'ed him yet?
我试了  但所有数据库都查不到他的指纹
Look, I'm trying, but his fingerprints aren't in any database,
这点很奇怪
which is weird,
因为我以为他一定会有犯罪记录呢
because I thought for sure he'd have a criminal record.
为什么
How come?
他不是第一次身负多伤了
It's not the first time this guy has mixed it up--
身上有多处旧枪伤
old gunshot wounds,
手上有习武结下的厚茧
callused hands from martial arts training,
断过的骨头比柯受良还多
more broken bones than Evel Knievel.
看他拍的片子吓死你
You're not gonna believe his x-rays.
我的无名尸哪去了
Where is my John Doe?
尸体呢
我走的时候还在这儿呢
He was right there when I left.
我就出去了一小会
I-I was only gone a minute.
我知道他刚刚还在
I know he was right there.
我正打算给他开膛破肚呢
I was just about to cut him open.
现在他可真是不存在了
Well, now he really doesn't exist.
一具尸体怎么会从停尸间里凭空消失呢
How does a body just vanish from a morgue?
不知道  但托马斯·盖奇有这个本事
I don't know, but Thomas Gage does.
还记得他曾说过
Remember what he said--
你以为你掌握的证据都会消失无踪
Whatever you think you have is going away?
这事他也有份
He's in on this.
埃斯波  盖奇转移去扣押中心了吗
Espo, did Gage get transferred to Central Booking yet?
没  他还关在我们这儿
No, he's still in holding.
他得给我们老实交代
He's gonna give us some answers.
他跑哪去了
Where the hell is this guy?
之前还在  我
He was here. I-I--
我亲自锁的他
I secured him myself.
封锁分局
Lock down the precinct.
好的  马上
All right. Move.
灵书妙探
第四季 第十五集
老爸
Hey, Dad.
我昨晚想等你来着  但你回来得好晚
I tried to wait up, but you must have gotten in really late.
身不由己啊  嫌犯离奇失踪
Not by choice. Our suspect pulled a Houdini,
所以他们封锁了整个警局
so they locked down the entire station.
但那时  化名为托马斯·盖奇的
But by then, the mysterious steely killer,
神秘的冷血杀手
going by the nom de guerre of Thomas Gage,
早就不知所踪了
was long gone.
我要给这案子做笔记
I'm writing up notes on this case.
这可是我下本书的绝佳题材啊
Solid-gold material for my next book.
等等  那个把无名氏扔出窗外的人吗
Wait. The guy who threw John Doe out the window,
他逃走了
he escaped?
不过那是在他
Uh-huh, but only after
精心策划将无名尸偷出停尸间之后
orchestrating the theft of John Doe's body from the morgue.
这个情节多妙啊
How awesome is that?
对那个失职让尸体被窃的人不怎么妙
Not so awesome if you're the person who let it happen.
宝贝  不是你的责任
Oh, honey, it's not your fault.
当时我守着尸体  一个朋友来电话
I was with that body, but a friend called,
我就去一边聊天了  我没
and I stepped away to talk. I didn't--
好了  先听我说
Okay, hang on. Listen to me.
我很欣慰你当时不在
I'm glad you weren't there
因为会偷走尸体的人
because the kind of person who took John Doe's body
肯定也会毫不犹豫地
is the kind of person who wouldn't think twice
对妨碍他的人痛下杀手
about hurting whoever got in the way.
我还以为跟法医一起工作
Still, I thought working with Dr. Parish,
绝对不会发生由于我的失误
there'd be zero chance I'd make a mistake
而影响到病人的事件
that would affect a patient.
毕竟  这怎么可能呢
I mean, how could I, right?
可我还是搞砸了
Well, I found a way.
宝贝  知道吗
Y-you know, honey,
如果这份实习的工作不那么合适的话
if this internship isn't the right fit,
我相信蕾妮会谅解的
I'm sure Lanie would understand.
不行
No.
既然帕里什医生给了我这个机会
Dr. Parish gave me this opportunity,
我就不能半途而废
and I want to see it through.
如何
Well?
我们认为无名氏遇害的公寓
The apartment where John Doe was killed,
是托马斯·盖奇之前居住的地方
we think thomas gage was squatting there.
-结果  -我不管盖奇曾经住在哪
- Turns-- - I don't care where Gage was
除非这能告诉我他现在在哪
unless it tells me where he is now.
但我也很想知道
But I'm very interested in knowing
他是怎么在你们眼皮子底下从牢房溜出去的
how he got out of that holding cell on your watch.
长官  目前我们也不清楚
We're not clear on that, Sir.
但我们知道他是怎么离开分局的
But we do know how he left this precinct.
我猜他是从后门偷溜的
I assume he snuck out of the back exit.
其实他是从正门大摇大摆出去的
Actually, he went out through the front door.
这张照片是他往大堂走时拍下的
This is him heading to the lobby.
他从哪弄到的警服
Where did this man get a uniform?
从更衣室偷的
He stole it from the locker room.
查查他还干了什么
Find out what else he did.
去查监控录像  追查他的一举一动
Check our security video and retrace his steps.
我要知道他都做了什么
I want to know every move that he made.
遵命
Okay.
盖奇总是走在我们前面
Gage has been two steps ahead of us this whole time.
不仅如此  他一定还有其他同伙
Not only that, but he must have a partner
才能从停尸间把尸体偷走
who took John Doe from the morgue.
这些还是解释不了他为什么要穿上警服
Which still doesn't explain why he ended up wearing those blues.
何必冒险偷警服呢
Why risk stealing a uniform
他明明可以就那么走出警局
when he could've just walked out of the building?
我知道原因  因为他要在分局里找些东西
I'll tell you why. He needed something inside our precinct.
他入侵了我们的数据库
The guy got into our database.
-找什么东西  -不是找东西
- Looking for what? - Not what.
而是找人
Who.
皇后区的特雷西·麦格拉
Tracy McGrath of Queens.
他搜索了她  我想我知道他找什么
He ran her name, and I think I know why.
她的住址没登记
Her address is unlisted.
如果落网只是盖奇计划的一部分呢
What if getting arrested was part of Gage's plan?
这样他就可以入侵数据库查到特雷西的地址了
So he could access our data for Tracy's address.
伙计们  尽力搜索有关特雷西的资料
All right, you guys pull up everything you can on Tracy.
我跟卡塞尔这就去看看
Castle and I will go over there now.
好
Okay.
她的手机直接转到语音信箱了
Her phone's going straight to voice mail.
她跟这一切有什么关联
What is her connection to all this?
盖奇为何对她这么有兴趣
Why is Gage so interested in her?
如果幸运  她或许知道盖奇的真实身份
With any luck, she knows who Gage really is.
特雷西·麦格拉
Tracy McGrath?
纽约警局
NYPD.
卡塞尔
Castle.
埃斯波  我们来晚了
Espo, yeah, we got here too late.
她后脑中了一枪
Uh, she's got one to the back of the head.
你通知一下蕾妮  让她把鉴证组也带来
Can you call Lanie and get her to bring C.S.U. down here?
好  我着手办
Yeah. I'm on it.
盖茨警监
Captain Gates,
特雷西·麦格拉也被盖奇杀害了
looks like Tracy McGRrath was Gage's next victim.
我们掌握她什么情况
What do we know about her?
她33岁  没有亲人
Well, she's 33, no family.
是研究基金会的一位科学家
A scientist at a research foundation.
好  找她的同事问话
All right. Talk to her coworkers.
查明盖奇为什么要置她于死地
Find out why Gage would've wanted her dead.
看来她死了有一阵子了
Looks like she's been here a while.
这一点也不稀奇
Yeah, well, it makes sense.
盖奇昨晚就逃跑了
Gage escaped last night.
动作比我们快了10个小时
He had a 10-hour lead on us.
你留在原地
You stay put.
我去看看屋里其他地方
I'm gonna check the rest of the place.
卡塞尔
Castle...
人都去哪了
Where is everybody?
我们通常会先于警员到达现场
We usually beat the uniforms to the scenes.
他们总不想急匆匆地来然后傻站着
It's not like they want to hurry and stand around.
这次我不会让死者再离开我的视线了
Just so you know, I'm not letting this victim out of my sight.
-真荒唐  -怎么了
- Crazy. - What is?
像理查德·卡塞尔那样
The fact that Richard Castle,
从不会内疚自责的人
a man unburdened by regret and guilt,
怎么会有一个责任心这么强的女儿
has a child that carries the weight of the world.
那具尸体消失了不是你的责任
It is not on you that a dead man came up missing.
那样的事多久发生一次
Well, how often does something like that happen anyway?
从未发生过  所以别担心  这事很怪
It never happens, honey. So relax. It was a freak thing.
尸体不会不翼而飞的
Bodies just don't disappear.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett?
Detective Beckett.
好吧  我看见血迹了
Okay, I see where the blood stain is.
尸体呢
Where is the body?
你没事吧
You okay?
没事  你呢
Yeah. You?
你是什么人
Who are you?
要带我们去哪里
Where the hell are you taking us?
无论是哪儿
Wherever it is...
是在地下很深处
It's way down.
这究竟是什么地方
What is this place?
不知道  一头雾水
I don't know. I have no idea.
里克·卡塞尔也有词穷的时候
Rick Castle at a loss for words?
破天荒头一遭吧
That must be a first for you.
索菲亚·特纳
Sophia Turner?
你好  里克
Hello, Rick.
欢迎来到中情局
Welcome to the CIA.
对  是她
Yeah, that's her.
特雷西已经在牛顿基金会为我工作五年了
Tracy's worked for me at the Newton foundation for five years.
昨天我还和她说过话
I just talked to her yesterday.
我们争论雪佛兰古董车的优点
We debated the merits of the Chevy Corvair.
她喜欢古典车
She's a classic car buff.
生前喜欢
She was.
特雷西到底负责什么工作
And what kind of work did Tracy do exactly?
不会招来杀身之祸的工作  你是这意思吗
It wouldn't get you killed, if that's what you're asking.
特雷西拥有应用数学的博士学位
Tracy had a PhD in applied mathematics.
她研发统计模型
She'd been developing statistical models
以预测气候变化的影响
to predict the affects of climate change.
她有树敌吗
Did she have any enemies,
有没有人会对她不利
anybody who might want to do her harm?
就我所知没有
None that I know of.
等等
Hold on.
昨天有件奇怪事
There was something, yesterday.
她大概下午三点突然离开办公室
Uh, she left the office rather suddenly, about 3:00.
她没跟我打招呼  就那么消失了两个小时
She didn't check in with me. She was just gone for two hours.
那可不是她的风格
That wasn't like her.
你知道她去了哪里吗
Do you have any idea where she went?
不知道  我问她时
No, and when I asked,
她似乎不想说
she didn't seem to want to tell me.
我们要查看她的电脑
We're gonna need access to her computer,
电邮  文档等一切资料
her e-mails, her documents, everything.
全在我们的服务器里
It's all on our server.
我在这里就可以登录
I can log into there from here.
秘密地下总部
Secret underground headquarters?
和007电影有得一拼
This is straight out of James Bond.
卡塞尔  你在回避问题
Castle, you're avoiding the question.
索菲亚·特纳是什么人  你怎么认识她的
Who's Sophia Turner? How do you know her?
说来话长
Uh, it's a... long story.
那你就长话短说吧
Well, I'll take the short version.
还是我来揭谜底吧
Let me give it to you.
已经有
What has it been,
十二年了吧
12 years?
十一年半
11 and a half.
我们是里克为他的第一本德里克·斯道姆小说
Rick and I met when he was just beginning to do research
做调研的时认识的
on his first Derrick Storm novel.
他想近距离亲身观察
He wanted an up-close-and-personal look
中情局女特工的生活
at the life of a female CIA agent.
所以我就让他如愿了
So I gave him one.
你就是克莱拉·斯瑞克
You're Clara Strike,
德里克·斯道姆系列小说里的克莱拉·斯瑞克
the Clara Strike from the Derrick Storm books?
我不敢肯定自己就是克莱拉·斯瑞克
I wouldn't say that I am Clara Strike,
但我想我还是给了里克一些灵感
but I'd like to think that I inspired Rick in some small way.
真是太有意思了
Well, that is just fascinating.
-气色不错呀  -你也是
- You look good. - You, too.
我不想打扰你们老友重聚
Okay, so I hate to interrupt this reunion,
但是我们被非法扣留了
but we're being illegally detained,
至少我是不情愿的
at least I am.
不是扣留
This is not a detention.
而是任务报告  纽约警局批准的
This is a debriefing, approved by the NYPD.
欢迎打给泰德·麦奎因核实
Feel free to call Ted McQuinn.
你是说警部
The chief of detectives?
他向我保证你会全力配合
He assured me you'd give us your full cooperation.
请告诉我你掌握的托马斯·盖奇的一切情况
I need to know everything you know about Thomas Gage.
不  你得先跟我说清楚到底是什么情况
No. Not until you tell me what the hell is going on here.
好吧
Fine.
不过这会涉及到
But that would be getting into
事关国家安全的高度机密
highly classified information regarding national security,
如果你泄露此机密
which, if you were to reveal it to anyone,
将被裁定为
would be considered a treasonable offense
叛国罪
against the United States of America,
并会被判处死刑
punishable by death.
那么  你还想知道吗
So... you still want to know?
托马斯·盖奇于97年从海豹突击第6分队招至麾下
We recruited Thomas Gage out of seal team six in 1997.
机智  训练有素  精通11种语言
Smart, highly trained, fluent in 11 languages,
他曾是我们的王牌特工
Gage was our most effective asset.
我们派他去世界各地的冲突地区和国家
We sent him into conflict zones, failed states all over the world.
盖奇能处理好任何情况
Gage was adept in every situation.
不幸的是  他变节了
Unfortunately, he went rogue.
根据国家安全局拦截的情报
Based on N.S.A. intercepts,
我们相信盖奇试图发动一起灾难性事件
we believe that Gage is trying to initiate a catastrophic event,
这对国家安全构成紧迫威胁
which poses an imminent threat to the country.
这么说
So...
被盖奇推出窗外的男子  是中情局特工
That man that Gage pushed out the window, he was CIA.
加里·哈勃  顶尖特工之一
Gary Harper. One of our best.
我们掌握了盖奇的踪迹
We got a tip on Gage's whereabouts.
派哈勃将其逮捕
We sent Harper to bring him in.
显然  行动失败了
Obviously, that operation didn't go as planned.
之后  是你们从停尸间偷走了尸体
At which point, you took the body from the morgue.
这可是国家安全危机
This is a national security crisis.
我们可不希望纽约警局碍手碍脚
We didn't want the NYPD underfoot.
很高兴知道这点
Well, good to know.
你们是怎么调查到特雷西·麦格拉的
So how did you guys get on to Tracy McGrath?
我们监控了你们分局的数据
We monitored data from your precinct.
发现了此人  但不幸的是
Her name came up, but unfortunately,
特工赶到时  她已经遇害了
by the time our agent got there, she was already dead.
盖奇为什么要杀她
So why did Gage kill her?
我们希望你知道呢
We were hoping you would know.
你可以接电话
You can go ahead and answer that.
我没打算不接
Yeah, I was planning on it.
介意用免提接听吗
Would you mind terribly putting it on speaker?
埃斯波  免提开着
Espo, you're on speaker.
警部发下话来
Yeah, so, word came down from chief of D's.
他说你在实行什么特殊任务
He said you were on some kind of special assignment.
这是怎么回事
What's that about?
说来话长
Uh, it's a long story.
特雷西·麦格拉方面有什么进展
What do you got on Tracy McGrath?
可能与案子无关
It may be nothing,
她昨天曾翘班两个小时
but she ditched work yesterday for two hours.
她的日程安排上作了记号
She has a notation in her day planner,
只写了"潘朵拉"
but all it says is "Pandora."
我等下打给你
You know what? Let me get back to you.
"潘朵拉"是什么
What's Pandora?
据我们所知
According to the chatter,
"潘朵拉"是盖奇任务的代号
Pandora is the code name for Gage's mission,
就是说这位麦格拉女士也牵涉其中
which means that the McGrath woman is mixed up in it.
我们掌握的情况已全数告知
Now the two of you know as much as we do.
在这个案件上  你的表现很出色
Look, you have done impressive work on this case.
我要你负责搜捕托马斯·盖奇的行动
I want you to take the lead in finding Thomas Gage.
索菲亚
Sophia--
马丁  我们已经无计可施了
Martin, we are up against the wall.
中情局被禁止进行国内调查
The CIA is barred from domestic investigation.
这种情况不是该联调局出手吗
Well, isn't that what the FBI is for?
托马斯·盖奇是幕前棋子
Thomas Gage is a hired gun.
我们不知道他受雇于谁  牵涉有多深
We don't know who he works for or how deep this goes.
我希望你继续调查此案
All I am asking is that you continue your investigation,
我们得到他的情报会跟你们共享
and we will share all information we get on him.
有什么条件
And what's the catch?
礼尚往来
That you do the same,
而且你只向我汇报
and that you report only to me.
此事只能你知我知
This has to stay between us.
技术人员已经在你们手机里安装了程序
Our techs have uploaded icons on both your phones,
可以直接连线我的电话
which will connect you to my direct line.
你们也看到盖奇的手段了
You've seen what Gage is capable of.
他是我们最危险的特工之一
He's one of our most dangerous operatives,
我毫不怀疑  无论他在计划什么
and I have no doubt that, whatever he is planning,
他完全有能力使之成为事实
he is completely capable of carrying out.
我也不想让你身处险境
I wouldn't put you in this position,
但必须有人来阻止他
but this man has to be stopped.
我可以寄希望于你们的帮助吗
Can I count on you for your help?
可以
Yes.
你意识到这代表着什么吗
Do you realize what this means?
我们成了特工
We're spies.
这就好像是《谍影重重》
This is like being in a Jason Bourne movie,
只是变节特工是反派  中情局成了好人
only he's the bad guy, and the CIA are the good guys.
-言之尚早  -对了
- That remains to be seen. - Ooh, wait.
我得看看他们装的直通电话符号
I've gotta see those direct-dial icons they put on our phones.
为什么我的是个紧急按钮
Hey. Why is mine a panic button?
看来她真的非常了解你
I guess she really does know you well.
好吧
Okay.
-你生气了  -我没生气
- You're upset. - I'm not upset.
那你是怎么了
Then what are you?
我只是对新的指挥架构
I am just a little bit uncomfortable
有点小情绪
with the new command structure.
我不喜欢对警局手足隐瞒秘密
I don't like keeping secrets from my own people.
你确定和索菲亚无关吗
You're sure this isn't about Sophia?
是的  关她什么事
No, why would it be?
我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
可能是因为我拿她做了人物原型
Maybe because I based a character on her.
少自作多情了  卡塞尔
Oh, don't flatter yourself, Castle.
那又不是多大的荣誉
It's not that big an honor.
好极了  因为索菲亚和我们同一战线
Good, because Sophia is on our side.
我们在同一阵营里
We're on the same team.
而你对此毫不担忧
And that doesn't concern you?
不觉得这会破坏团队凝聚力吗
You don't think that that will undermine our unit cohesion?
为了国家安全着想
Hey, I am willing to let that slide
我就不计较那些了
in the interest of national security.
我也一样
Yeah, well, I guess I am, too.
只是当我发现你还和
It's just, I might have been a little bit taken aback
其他人一起做研究...
to find out that you had...
有点吃惊罢了
researched with someone else.
我和她之间的关系跟咱俩之间是不一样的
Look, it was never the way it is with you and me.
我只是跟着她混了一段时间
I just hung out with her for a while
为了使克莱拉·斯瑞克更真实些
to lend some authenticity to Clara Strike.
很久之前的事了  持续时间很短
It was a brief moment a long time ago.
再说了  妮基·希特
And besides, Nikki Heat
可是个比其更复杂
is a far more complex and...
更微妙的人物
nuanced character.
真的
She is.
而我的写作经验也更丰富了
And I'm a far more experienced writer,
风格更加成熟
more mature.
忽悠过头了
One out of two is...
你跟她混了多久
So how long did the two of you hang out?
一年
A year?
那叫持续时间很短吗
That's your idea of a brief moment?
我那时初出茅庐  有很多东西需要她教
I was young, and she had a lot to teach me.
可不是嘛
Ha! Yeah, I'll bet.
我是说间谍的神秘世界
A-about the shadowy world of espionage.
我这么问吧  借研究之名
Let me ask you this-- how many other women
你还"半跟踪"过多少个女人
have you semi-stalked in the name of research?
这是个陷阱问题吗
Is this a trick question?
算了  我根本就不想知道
You know what? I don't even want to know.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett,
卡塞尔先生  你们能回来真好
Mr. Castle, good of you to drop by.
跟我说说你们的特别任务
So tell me about this special assignment of yours.
很抱歉不行  长官
I'm afraid I can't, sir.
你说什么
Excuse me?
没错  此事属于"非需勿知"
Yes, it's on a need-to-know basis.
我需要知道
And I need to know.
长官  我想警部在这件事上
Sir, I think that the Chief of Detectives
会支持我的做法
would back me up on this one.
我们走着瞧
We'll see about that.
你看见她有多抓狂了吗
Did you see how mad she was?
老天  真是太棒了
God, that was so good.
好了...
So...
说真的  出什么事了
Seriously, what's going on?
伙计们  抱歉  我们真的不能透露
Guys, I'm sorry. We really can't talk about it.
得了吧  我们谁跟谁啊
Come on. This is us.
不行  抱歉了
No. Hey, sorry, boys.
这是机密  最高机密
Classified. Top secret.
只能我们知道
Our eyes only.
一级戒备
Defcon 1.
要是告诉你了
And if I did tell you,
我就得杀了你
well, then I'd have to kill you.
-那就试试看  -事实上  我做不...
- Yeah? Good luck with that. - Yeah, realistically, that's not--
-我声明遮遮掩掩太烂了  -没错
- I'm gonna go on record and say that this sucks. - It sucks.
晓得了  还是继续调查特雷西·麦格拉
And noted. Now let's move on to Tracy McGrath.
她在下班之后去了哪里
Where'd she go after she left work?
根据她的易行通
Well, according to her E-Z Pass,
她驱车上了新泽西高速公路
she drove down the Jersey turnpike
在纽瓦克机场附近下了公路
and exited somewhere near Newark Airport.
我们还在查她去了哪里
We're still trying to figure out where she went.
可能答案仍在犯罪现场
Maybe the answer's still at the crime scene.
没有强行闯入和争斗痕迹
There's no signs of forced entry or struggle.
看来她认识凶手  让他进入了公寓
It's like she knew her killer, she let him in.
她走在凶手前面
She walked in front of him,
他朝她后脑勺开了一枪
and he shot her in the back of the head.
也就是说她认识盖奇
Which means she knew Gage.
气候学家怎么会和
So how is a climate scientist
一个残忍的前中情局探员扯上关系
mixed up with a ruthless ex-CIA agent?
她又怎么会和潘朵拉有联系
And how is she connected to Pandora?
这里一定有能将两者联系起来的线索
There's gotta be something here that ties them together.
她对车的品味还不错嘛
Well, she has excellent taste in cars.
这里有本1967年产
Here's an auto repair manual
庞蒂克GTO的维修手册
for a 1967 Pontiac GTO.
有意思
That's funny.
钥匙放在昨天收到的一堆信上
The keys are sitting on a pile of yesterday's mail.
死之前  她还开过这车
She drove it before she died.
但街上没有GTO
Except there's no GTO in the street.
车库里也没有  车呢
Or in the garage, so where's the car?
我在信用卡上发现了一条常规收费记录
I see a recurring charge on her credit card.
看来她每月都会付给
It looks like she's paying 100 bucks a month
弗兰奇停车场一百美元
for Frenchie's Parking.
才一百  在曼哈顿可不止这个数
100 bucks? That's not gonna get you a space in Manhattan.
没错  账单信息显示弗兰奇停车场在
Bingo. Billing info says that Frenchie's is in
新泽西州的伊丽莎白港口
Elizabeth Port, New Jersey.
就在纽瓦克机场附近
That's right near Newark Airport.
特雷西的神秘之旅开的是这辆GTO
So the mystery ride Tracy took has to do with the GTO.
就是它了
There it is.
这可是经典的汽车城[底特律]车
Now that is some classic Motor City iron.
十米长车身  罗契斯特的四排管
400 cubic inches with a Rochester 4-barrel
有360马力
and 360 horsepower.
-你了解大马力车  -是的
- You know muscle cars? - Oh, yeah.
改天我们该去赛道上比比  卡塞尔
We should go to the track sometime, Castle.
看看谁会被套圈[lap有舔的意思]
See who laps who.
你觉得特雷西为什么会翘班来到这里
So why do you think Tracy took off work to come down here?
也许是要驱车到某个秘密的
Maybe to drive it to a clandestine
潘朵拉相关的会合地点
Pandora-related, uh, rendezvous?
不是  看看车上的积灰
No. Look at the dust on this.
这车停在这里有一阵了
This hasn't gone anywhere in a while.
你看  卡塞尔
Castle, look.
也许她在汽车后备箱里藏了东西
Maybe she came to stash something in the trunk.
有手印  说明有人动过后备箱
Handprints, indicating someone's been in there.
没错
Yeah.
这可不是原车设备
That is not original equipment.
是的  八成这就是她来此地的原因
No, but it's probably why she came here.
等等  等一下
Wait-- wait a minute. Wait a minute.
还不知道这里面有什么
We don't know what's in there.
对  这是唯一能知道的方法
Yeah, well, there's only one way to find out.
但里面可能是潘朵拉
Yeah, but it might be Pandora,
就像潘朵拉魔盒  打开它之后
as in "Pandora's box," as in opening that
就会释放出无法阻止的罪恶
could unleash an unstoppable tide of evil.
卡塞尔  那个是神话故事
Castle, that's a myth.
我那是比喻
I'm speaking metaphorically.
盖奇在酝酿一起灾难性事件  对吧
Gage is planning a catastrophic event, right?
如果箱子里有末日装置
So what if there's a doomsday device
而你开箱的时候就会启动怎么办
in that case set to go off when you open it?
而零点位置就定在这个新泽西州的室内停车场吗
And Ground Zero is a parking garage in New Jersey?
我有点怀疑
I doubt it.
我只...
I ju--
这是军用手机和扰频器
That is a military-grade cell phone and a scrambler.
是间谍的装备
That's spy equipment.
特雷西来到这里只为打电话
Tracy came here to make a phone call,
我打赌她拨的最后一通电话号码
and I bet you that the last number she dialed
仍在手机上
is still on the phone.
关上箱子  转身
Close the case and turn around.
举起手来
Hands in the air.
盖奇
Gage.
把枪和手机放在地上
Your weapon and phones on the ground.
不是吧  该你举起手吧
Really? You put your hands in the air.
把手机放在地上
Your phones on the ground.
我可刚升级
I just upgraded.
这是新电话
This is a brand-new phone.
好了...
Now...
恐怕你们不会喜欢接下来的事
I'm afraid you're not gonna like what comes next.
卡塞尔
Castle.
卡塞尔  你在干什么
Castle, what are you doing?
做肉盾  为你挡子弹啊
Bracing myself to shield you from a hail of bullets.
你可真英勇啊
Yeah, well, that's very gallant of you,
不过不用撑了
but you can stop bracing.
我想他走了
I think he left.
往事在我眼前一一掠过
Man, my life was passing before my eyes.
有点忘记时间了
I think I lost track of time.
你熟悉后备箱插销吗
What do you know about trunk latches?
坏消息是
Well, the bad news is,
后备箱没有设计成从里面打开
this one was not designed to open from the inside.
那好消息是什么
And the good news?
至少这次  我们没被铐在一起
At least this time, we're not handcuffed together.
这里还挺宽敞的
Mm. You know, it's surprisingly roomy in here.
也没那么宽敞
Well, it's not that roomy.
这里的空气迟早会被耗尽
Sooner or later, we're gonna run out of air.
我们得从这里出去
We gotta get out of here.
也许有人会找到我们
Well, maybe somebody will find us.
卡塞尔  我们被关在长期停车场
Castle, we are locked in the trunk of a car
一辆车的后备箱里
in long-term parking.
在有人意识到我们失踪之前还有很长时间
It's gonna be hours before anyone realizes that we're missing.
你觉得谁会找到我们
Who do you think is gonna find us?
我只是觉得  在这种情况下
I just feel, in situations like this,
有信念是很重要的
it's important to have faith.
你是不是按了紧急按钮
You pressed the panic button, didn't you?
要说紧急情况
Well, if there was ever a time to panic,
-我想就是现在了  -我
- I think this was it. - I am--
-你应该感谢我  -才不呢
- You should be thanking me. - No.
我才不要等着你女友来救我呢
I am not gonna be rescued by your girlfriend.
过去点  卡塞尔
Move, Castle.
-你要干  -我要往里伸点
- What are you-- - I need to get under there.
你在   你在干嘛
What are you-- what are you doing?
我拿到了
I got it.
什么东西
What?
这个  来
This. Here.
插进去了吗
Is it in?
再往左点
To the left.
好了  插吧
Okay. Push.
往后躺一点
Scoot down.
-成功了  -干得好
- Yes. - Nice.
为你们准备的
For you.
我想这是你的配枪
I believe this is yours.
琼斯特工在停车场找到的
Agent Jones found it in the parking structure.
找到车真是干得太棒了
Finding the car was great work.
我想它就是我们所需要的突破点
I think it might just be the break we need.
我可不敢独吞所有功劳
Well, I can't take all the credit.
是啊  发现车子的人可是莱恩警探
Yeah, especially since it was Detective Ryan who found it.
不管怎样  电话显然是关键
Well, in any case, the phone is obviously key,
不然盖奇也不会拼命去找
or else Gage wouldn't have gone after it.
特雷西·麦格拉在她死的那天用过这个电话
Well, Tracy McGrath used it on the day she died.
也许她打给某个同潘朵拉有关的人
Maybe she called someone connected to Pandora...
然后盖奇杀掉她  拿走电话
And then Gage eliminated her and took the phone
不留任何活口
to tie off all loose ends.
但这仍然说明不了盖奇在哪儿
Which still doesn't explain where Gage is now
特雷西电话打给谁了
or who Tracy called.
一旦我们追踪到那通电话  就会知道了
Well, we'll find that out once we track the call she made.
但电话被盖奇拿走了
But Gage took the phone.
你既不知道她打出的号码
How can you do that when you don't know what number she called
也不知道她用什么号码   你要怎么追查
or even the number she called it from?
用最酷的玩具咯
By using all the coolest toys.
查下取道收费高速  昨天下午三点时
Bring up Newton Foundation to Frenchie's parking,
从牛顿基金会到弗兰奇停车场需要多久
commute time by car at 3:00 p.m. yesterday via the turnpike.
41分钟
41 minutes.
在华盛顿大桥那里有起小交通事故
There was a fender bender on the G.W. Bridge.
加上她走到车那里所需的时间
Factoring the time it would have taken her to get to her car,
假设她3点45分抵达
let's say she got there at 3:45 p.m.
筛选出接下来15分钟打出的电话
Pull up all cell phone traffic for the next 15 minutes.
电话会经过最近的手机信号发射塔
The call would've pinged off the nearest cell tower.
人在纽瓦克机场的南边
This guy at the south end of the Newark Airport,
则筛选得到
which processed...
15分钟内共有5429通电话
5,429 calls in the 15-minute time frame.
只显示打往纽约和新泽西的
Filter it to calls just to New York and New Jersey.
还有4112通
That takes us to 4,112.
现在只要投币式公用电话和没登记的手机
Now just pay phones and unregistered cells.
降到712通
Down to 712.
通话时间一分钟以内的
Calls under a minute.
她肯定言简意赅
She would've kept it brief.
还有42通
We're at 42.
三角定位这42个手机信号
Okay, now triangulate those 42 signals,
看哪通电话的信号
and let's see which one originates
离停车场最近
closest to that parking structure.
找到了  昨天下午3点56分
Got it. Yesterday at 3:56 p.m.
此通电话经过发射塔
This call pinged off the tower
打给了布鲁克林的一个投币式公用电话
and was routed to a pay phone in Brooklyn.
普利茅斯街和金色大街的十字路口
Uh, intersection of Plymouth and Gold.
应该就是特雷西·麦格拉打的那个号码
It's gotta be the number Tracy Mcgrath called .
找到能看到那个电话的摄像头
Get me eyes on that pay phone.
调出昨天下午3点56分所有的当地监控录像
Any local surveillance from yesterday at 3:56 p.m.
找到了
Found one.
正在剔除
Isolating now.
有段录像  下午3点56分
There's a video. At 3:56 p.m.
拉近点
Zoom in.
他手上拿着扰频器  就是我们要找的人
He's got a scrambler. That's our guy.
他看起来眼熟
He looks familiar.
停
Freeze there.
天啊
Oh, my god.
这不可能
That's impossible.
他不是已经死了吗
He's supposed to be dead.
他是谁
Who is he?
尼尔森·布莱克利博士
Dr. Nelson Blakely.
数学教授
Mathematics professor.
中情局传奇
He was a legend at the agency.
天才
A genius.
我们的顾问
Consulted for us,
但于2002年去世
but died in 2002,
至少直到刚才我们是这么认为的
or at least that's what we thought until just now.
他伪造了自己的死亡
So he faked his own death.
这事越来越有趣了
This just keeps getting better.
不是这样的
No, it doesn't,
以他的能耐  不能说有趣
not with what this man is capable of.
布莱克利帮我们设计以数学为基础的预测模式
Blakely designed math-based predictive models for us,
用于创造地缘政治的变化
models to help create geopolitical change.
此话怎讲
What do you mean by that?
局里带着问题找到他
The agency would bring him a problem--
我们怎样做才能阻止A国家得到炸弹
How can we prevent country "A" from getting the bomb
或者引致B国家政权更迭
or cause regime change in country "B."
布莱克利找到了解决办法
Blakely found solutions
运用他所谓的关键理论
using what he called Linchpin theory.
他的方法是找到能引起
His approach was to find a small event
大冲突的小事件
that could trigger a large event.
例如引起第一次世界大战的
Like the assassination of Archduke Ferdinand
萨拉热窝事件
causing World War I.
完全正确
Exactly.
他曾说过  你只需推倒一块多米诺骨牌
He once said that you only had to knock over one domino,
如果是至关重要的那块
but if it was the right domino,
其它的就会顺势倒下
the rest would fall.
如果布莱克利就是策划潘朵拉的人
If Blakely is the one who planned Pandora,
那将远超出最坏的设想
this is beyond a worst-case scenario.
布莱克利只是个雇员  跟盖奇一样
Blakely is just a hired gun, like Gage.
他可不是幕后黑手
He's not the one behind this.
特纳探员  我找到了
Agent Turner, I've got it.
录像的清晰度足以读出他的唇语
The video's clean enough to track his lip movement.
他说了什么
What's he saying?
周四下午五点来见我
Meet me Thursday at 5:00 p.m.
象 A5
Bishop A-5,
象  C4  卒  E3
bishop C-4, pawn E-3.
国际象棋走法吗
Chess moves?
布莱克利曾是世界级的国际象棋大师
Blakely was a world-class chess player.
是某种密码
It's some sort of code.
与加密数据库内所有加密模式做对比
Run that pattern against anything in the encryption database.
这个发现将我们带进了敏感地带
This takes us into a sensitive area.
不能让外人知道  我懂的
For your eyes only. I get it.
非常感谢你的帮助
Thank you so much for your help.
琼斯特工会带你们出去的
Agent Jones will show you out.
等下  盖奇怎么办
W-wait a minute. What about Gage?
我们得集中人力物力找到布莱克利
We need to invest all of our resources into finding Blakely.
他是此案的薄弱环节
He's the weak link here.
但如果你们发现与盖奇有关的线索
Right, but if you find something on Gage,
麻烦通知我们
you'll let us know.
当然  我们站在同一战线
Absolutely. We're in this together.
知道我怎么想的吗
You know what I think?
我觉得我们应该破解国际象棋密码
I think we should crack that chess code.
中情局能破解的  卡塞尔
The CIA can handle it, Castle.
凭他们的履历
With their track record?
我可不这么乐观
I'm not so sure.
我就那么一说
I'm just sayin'.
一旦我们成功破解密码
Look, we decipher that code,
就能避免一场灾难性事件的发生
we can save this country from a nameless cataclysmic event.
要是你想追查布莱克利就去吧
Look, if you want to go after Blakely, go ahead.
我是凶案探长
I'm a Homicide Detective.
我必须找到托马斯·盖奇
I have to find Thomas Gage,
而听从索菲亚·特纳指挥是找不到他的
and I can't do that by answering to Sophia Turner.
什么意思
What do you mean?
卡塞尔  他杀了两个人
He killed two people, Castle.
你觉得她对此在意吗
Do you think she even cares about that?
不  她还有别的事要做呢
No. She's got a whole different agenda.
比如拯救世界  我们站在同一阵线
Yeah, like saving the world. We're all on the same team here.
不  你站在她那边
No, you're on her team,
从你看她的眼神
cause the way you look at her,
你铁定没有站在我这边
you're sure as hell not on mine.
真有必要吗
Seriously?
这可是保密机构
This is a secure facility.
我们不想泄密
We need to keep it that way.
我刚和阿丽克西斯谈完
I just had a talk with Alexis.
我很高兴你没反对这个实习
I am so pleased you are on board with this internship.
我只是被逼无奈
Because I was forced to be on board.
妈  你怎么会让这事发生呢
How could you let that happen, mother?
亲爱的 别傻了
Oh, darling, don't be silly.
你心情不好
And you're just in a foul mood
不过是因为跟贝克特吵架了
because you had a spat with Beckett.
我才没
I am not in a...
你怎么看出来的
How did you find out about that?
不  先别说  等我猜猜
No, wait. Let me guess.
贝克特告诉蕾妮
Beckett to Lanie
她再告诉阿丽克西斯  再传到你这儿
to Alexis to you.
看吧  这就是令我害怕的
See? This, this is what I was afraid of.
不过我得说清楚  我们可没吵架
For your information, we did not have a spat.
我今天只是选择待在家
I simply chose to work at home today.
忙于一件牵涉到消失的尸体和特别任务的案件
On a case involving vanishing bodies and special assignments.
不是吧  这事她也告诉你了
Really? She told you that, too?
-我现在还有隐私可言吗  -基本没有
- Is nothing sacred?  - Not much.
不过不管怎样  我不能跟你讨论这个案子
Yes, well, in any event, I'm not allowed to discuss it.
拜托  你以前也没因此闭嘴啊
Oh, please. When has that stopped you before?
显然我现在该定定规矩了
Well, clearly it's time i start setting some boundaries around here.
好吧
All right.
我只可以告诉你
I can tell you this much.
我现在在研究一个密码
I'm working on a code...
这个密码就由这三个棋子构成
involving these three chess pieces.
要是能破译出来  就能防止一场大灾难
The answer to which could avert a catastrophe.
两个象和一个卒  这能代表什么呢
Two bishops and a pawn. What could it mean?
我也不知道
I don't know. Ohh.
我一直在研究经典的棋路
I've been looking up classic strategies.
我看了菲舍尔  卡尔波夫
I've looked up famous chess matches
这些象棋大师的比赛
with Fischer, Karpov, Kasparov,
但都没发现这个阵局
but this pattern never occurs.
也许棋子跟国际象棋一点关系也没有
Maybe the pieces have nothing to do with the chess game.
也许它们代表了一些跟国际象棋完全
Maybe the pieces represent something else...
无关的东西
entirely.
贝克特
Yo, Beckett.
我没查到关于盖奇的线索  但记得你让我
Nothing on Gage, but remember you asked me
去查特雷西·麦格拉和一个叫做
to look for a link between Tracy Mcgrath
尼尔森·布莱克利的家伙之间的联系对吧
and some guy named Nelson Blakely?
没错
Yeah.
我发现了二人在十年前有关联
I found one from ten years ago.
特雷西曾和一帮她研究生朋友
Tracy and a bunch of her grad student friends
跟他们的教授  布莱克利博士
went on a white-water rafting trip
一同去浅滩漂流
with a Dr. Blakely, their professor,
不过他很不走运
although it wasn't a good time for him.
他在旅行中溺水丧生了
He drowned during the trip.
这么说他伪造了自己的死亡
So he faked his death
而特雷西也参与了
and Tracy was in on it.
谁装死  布莱克利吗
Who faked his death -- Blakely?
抱歉
Uh...I'm sorry.
不能告诉你
I can't tell you.
男人的忍耐是有限的
You know, a man can only take so much.
-你怎么来了  -我有所发现
- Hey. What are you doing here?  - I found something.
是关于布莱克利的
It's about Blakely.
你不是应该去告诉索菲亚吗
Well, shouldn't you tell Sophia about it?
她又不是我搭档
She isn't my partner.
你才是
You are.
我可以坐下吗
May I?
好吧
All right.
象  象  卒
Bishop, bishop, pawn.
我们知道布莱克利是个世界级的国际象棋大师
We know Blakely was a world-class chess player.
特雷西·麦格拉也下象棋  她有计时器
Tracy McGrath played, too. She had a game timer.
但是这种摆法根本毫无战术意义
Yet, this placement makes no tactical sense.
我猜你是有所发现了
I'm guessing you got a theory?
我认为这些棋子跟国际象棋本身没有关系
I don't think the pieces have anything to do with the game.
我认为布莱克利是给特雷西留下了一条加密的口信
I think Blakely was leaving Tracy a coded message,
告诉她去哪里找他
telling her where to meet him.
甚至有可能是他们下象棋的地方
Maybe even a place where they play chess.
好吧  大家经常在公园里下象棋
Okay, well, uh, people play chess in parks.
中心公园  华盛顿广场公园
Uh, Central Park, Washington Square Park --
这些都是跟人见面的好地方
those would be great places to meet up with someone
同时又不会引人注意
without drawing attention.
没错  要是每个棋子
Exactly. Now what if each piece
都代表了一个英文单词的首字母呢
stood for the first letter of a word?
象代表B  卒代表P
Bishop for "B," pawn for "P"?
好吧  字母B然后空七格
Okay, "B" and then seven spaces,
有可能是
that could be...
布鲁克林
Brooklyn.
布莱克利的电话就是从布鲁克林打出来的
And Blakely made his phone call from Brooklyn.
那就是布鲁克林  BBP
So Brooklyn -- b-b-p.
布鲁克林桥公园吗
Uh, Brooklyn... Bridge Park?
他们定在五点见  也就是半个小时以后
That meeting is at 5:00. That's in half an hour.
如果布莱克利去了  我们就能查明潘朵拉是什么
If Blakely shows, we can find out what Pandora is
还可以找到盖奇
and we can find Gage.
你觉得怎么样
What do you say?
布莱克利现在该到了
Blakely should've been here by now.
也许他知道特雷西已经死了
Maybe he knows that Tracy's dead
又或者盖奇已经杀了他
or maybe Gage already killed him.
我选择心存希望
I choose the audacity of hope.
照我看他会出现的
I say, he'll be here.
那你不是应该打给索菲亚吗
Well, then shouldn't you call Sophia?
要是我推理错误不就糗大了吗
And look like an ass if I'm wrong?
我不得不承认  我有点惊讶
You know, I have to admit, I'm actually kind of surprised
你以前居然从来都没有提过她
that you've never mentioned her before.
我不能说
I wasn't allowed to.
她是中情局的在职特工
She is an active CIA agent.
这样啊
I see.
要是你愿意的话
Look, if you want,
我可以回答你关于她的任何问题
I will answer any question you have about her --
你问什么都行
Anything at all.
不用了  谢谢
No. Thanks.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
确定  她的事跟我无关
Yeah, I mean, it's really none of my business.
好吧  那这件事就到此为止了
Okay. Well, we're done with it then.
好的
Fine.
那
So...
你们俩的关系到底有多亲密
how close were the two of you exactly?
他来了
There he is.
拜托  卡塞尔  是你自己说我可以随便问的
Come on, Castle. You said I could ask you anything.
不  我说真的  他来了
No, seriously. There he is.
布莱克利博士
Dr. Blakely.
恐怕你认错人了
I'm afraid you've mistaken me for someone else.
不  我没认错
No, there is no mistake.
你是怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
通过特雷西
Through Tracy.
她已经死了
She's dead.
如果他们能找到她  他们就能找到我
If they got to her, they can get to me.
我们得马上离开这儿
We need to leave here now.
我早就知道会有这么一天
I always knew this day would come.
但是特雷西
But Tracy...
布莱克利博士  到底是怎么回事
Dr. Blakely, what's going on?
潘朵拉是什么
What's Pandora?
我需要你开车带我去32号码头
I need you to drive me to Pier 32.
你现在没有讨价还价的资本
You're not in a position to bargain here.
我是自愿上车的  如果你不带我去我想去的地方
I got in this car voluntarily, and I'll get right back out
我就马上下车
if you don't take me where I want to go.
32号码头有什么
Okay, what's at Pier 32?
我们一到那儿
Once we're there,
我一定知无不言
I'll tell you what you want to know.
你是你所处领域的佼佼者
You were top of your field,
还是教授兼中情局的顾问
a professor, an advisor for the CIA.
为什么要伪造自己的死亡呢
Why fake your own death?
我为了中情局毁掉了不少国家
I brought down nations for the agency.
我扮演了上帝的角色  但是
I played God, but...
我的关键理论没考虑到人力的消耗
my Linchpin theory didn't factor in the human cost.
我知道他们永远都不会让我离开  只好装死
I knew they'd never let me leave, so I died
再重生
and was reborn.
唯一的知情人就是特雷西吗
And the only one who knew was Tracy?
她是我赖以生存的生命线
She was my lifeline.
她把顾问工作的方向转到了我的理论上
She steered consulting work my way.
我曾帮助非洲减低霍乱发生率
I helped reduce cholera in Africa.
我曾预言只要有一次非暴力反抗
I predicted that a lone act of civil disobedience
就会引发阿拉伯世界的起义和重组
would trigger an uprising and remake the Arab world.
我干过一些好事
I-I did good things.
是谁杀了特雷西
Who killed her?
和想要启动潘朵拉的是一个人
The same man that's trying to pull off Pandora.
你是说他们想要实施那个计划吗
You mean, they're trying to make it happen?
这比我想象的还要严重
This is even worse than I thought.
好了  交代吧
All right, talk.
我得先进去
I need to go inside first.
你不老实交代潘朵拉的事  就哪也别想去
You're not going anywhere until you tell me about Pandora.
潘朵拉是什么
What is it?
是我起草的一份白皮书的名字
It was the name of a white paper that I wrote.
为谁起草的
For whom?
一个智囊机构曾雇我
I was hired by a think tank
来分析美国安全系统的弱点
to identify weaknesses in U.S. security
以便他们对发现的弱点进行巩固和维护
so they could be shored up, protected.
我发现了一个令人担忧的弱点
I found an alarming vulnerability --
一个与经济相关的关键
a linchpin that was tied to the economy
能造成我们前所未见的
that would cause crisis and devastation
危机和破坏
beyond anything we'd ever seen.
多米诺骨牌会永不停歇地倒下去
The dominos would just never stop falling.
我让特雷西去跟进这个智囊团的进展情况
I asked Tracy to follow up with the think tank,
但却发现他们并不存在
but they don't exist.
不管他们是谁  我把会给美国
Whoever they are, I gave them the blueprint
带来毁灭的蓝图交给了他们
that will bring about the end of our country as we know it.
布莱克利博士
Dr. Blakely,
关键是什么
what is the linchpin?
怎么会有一群鸽子呢
A flock of pigeons?
布莱克利  你所谓的关键到底是什么
Blakely, the linchpin, what is it?
鸽子除非逃避捕食者的追击
Pigeons don't fly in flocks
不然它们是不会成群逃窜的
unless they're fleeing a predator.
他们来了
They're here.
等一下  等等
Wait. Wait! Wait! Wait!
布莱克利
Hey! Blakely!
挺住
Come on. Come on!
-贝克特  -抓稳了  卡塞尔
- Beckett!  - Hold on, Castle.
-抓稳了  -刹车  贝克特
- Hold on!  - Brake! Beckett!
抓稳了  卡塞尔
Hold on, Castle!
待  续